#### **SUMMARY**

A well-rounded software developer with experience developing and maintaining embedded software and mobile applications for aerospace and automotive customers. Extensive background in the full life-cycle of the software development process including design, development, test, debug, and maintenance.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Lead Software Engineer at Gentex (April 2018 - present)

Lead a small team of engineers designing, implementing, testing, debugging, and maintaining AWS cloud systems, Android mobile applications, and iOS mobile applications for several rear view mirror products and OEMs.

- Lead a small team of engineers, including creating a development process that ensures efficient, highly intuitive, reliable mobile applications, holding annual reviews, and holding one-on-ones.
- Acted as lead iOS developer on the HomeLink Connect app, Gentex' first production mobile application.
  - Wrote the majority of the Bluetooth code that communicates with rear view mirror products and the majority of the networking code that communicate with Gentex' AWS backend.
  - Handled the configuration including Apple developer accounts, certificates and provisioning profiles, continuous integration / continuous delivery, releasing internally and to the App Store.
- Prototyped many demonstration apps, including:
  - o Navigation (GPS & Google Maps) functionality.
  - o Bluetooth Low Energy functionality.
  - o Networking functionality, including REST & WebSockets.
  - Streaming video, including over RTSP & HTTP.

### Embedded Software Engineer at Gentex (May 2012 - April 2018)

Design, implement, test, debug, and maintain embedded software for several rear view mirror products and OEMs.

- Wrote embedded C/assembly software that is running in millions of vehicles.
- Integrated CAN communication, electrochromic dimming, lane departure warning, traffic sign recognition, Smartbeam, rear camera display, and TCP/IP software libraries into customer projects.
- Developed software that interfaces with a third party vision processing module, using the resulting information to provide lane keep assist, traffic sign recognition, and automatic high beam control.
- Participated in the development of an OSEK compliant operating system developed for internal projects.
- Developed software to support a new hardware system consisting of a dual core ARM Cortex A9 microcontroller with attached FPGA fabric, used for internal algorithm development and analysis.
  - o Ethernet, FPGA programming, watchdog, I2C, UART, and SPI microcontroller drivers.
  - o Application code to support the processor, the FPGA, and algorithms running on target.
  - Bootloader.
  - ARM NEON optimizations.
- Developed specifications and software to support customer specific CAN diagnostics.
- Developed software to support displaying images and animations on small LCD screens.

### Software Project Manager at Gentex (March 2011 - May 2012)

Manage the requirements, development, and test phases of embedded software for several rear view mirror products and OEMs.

• Worked with Opel, Jaguar, Land Rover, GM, and Nissan on Rear Camera Display and Smartbeam projects. Travelled to Japan, UK, and Mexico to support these activities.

# Faculty at Calvin College (2010)

• Taught a Circuits Analysis and Electronics lab.

## Technical Lead / Project Manager at DornerWorks (September 2008 - March 2011)

Manage the requirements, development, and test phases of embedded software for several products and OEMs.

- Led a team of up to 16 people working on GE Aviation's Software Common Operating Environment.
  - o DO-178B Tool Qualification
  - o DO-178B Problem Report Verification
  - DO-178B Structural Coverage Analysis of C code, Source to Object Analysis of C and Ada code, and Requirements Based Testing, focusing on the AFDX Ethernet Driver, Board Support Package, File System, and Health Monitor of the VxWorks Operating System.
- Led a team of up to 5 people doing requirements, development, and testing of software for Gentex' dimmable aircraft windows.

## Embedded Systems Engineer at DornerWorks (April 2006 - September 2008)

Design, implement, test, debug, and maintain embedded software.

- Developed a D0-178B Board Support package for the VxWorks Operating System of GE Aviation's Software Common Operating Environment.
- Developed the hardware and software for an electronic fan speed controller and wireless remote control.

### Intern at Smiths Industries Aerospace (now GE Aviation) (March 2005 - March 2006)

• Used C, National Instruments TestStand, and LabWindows to write test software.

## **Education**

# **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

Florida State University: 2012 - 2015

#### Master of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering - Digital and Computer Systems

Grand Valley State University: December 2010 Outstanding Graduate Student in Engineering, 2010

### **Bachelor of Science in Electrical and Computer Engineering**

Minor in Mathematics Calvin College: May 2006